<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Stay-wise | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/stay-wise/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-18T18:15:09+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How-To Stay Wise and Happy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/08/15/how-to-stay-wise-and-happy/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-15T16:37:02+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/08/15/how-to-stay-wise-and-happy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have jotted down a list of points on How-To stay <em>Wise</em> and <em>Happy</em>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Always focus on improving yourself first.</li>
<li>Go through life with an open-mind and you will find a lot of open doors.</li>
<li>Be strong and bold</li>
<li>Create new good habits</li>
<li>In order to change your life, change your thoughts and habits.</li>
<li>Old ways wont open new doors.</li>
<li>Get out of your comfort zone. Get uncomfortable in order to succeed.</li>
<li>Depend on no-one but yourself.</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need too many friends. Try to create powerful and true friendships.</li>
<li>Forgive people and forget bad feelings, but most importantly: learn from all situations. The weak can never forgive. Forgiveness is an attribute of the strong.</li>
<li>Always keep good company</li>
<li>Expand the edges of your mind. As Bruce Lee said become water.</li>
<li>Speak wisely. Be sure to taste your words before you spit them out.</li>
<li>Make peace with the Past. The past is like an achor holding us back. You must let go of who you were in order to become who you will be.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be to too nice to everyone. Niceness is seen as weakness and will be exploited. The problem with putting others first is that you&rsquo;ve taught them that you are second.</li>
<li>Never reveal your weaknesses to anyone.</li>
<li>Take decisions. Take bad decisions. Learn from those bad decisions and then take good decisions.</li>
<li>Always be you.</li>
<li>Remember same old thinking will not yield new results. Find out your old habit patterns and then act upon it.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
